But you know what, Satoru?
Before, I could only ever picture
a life of solitude for myself,
but now I have a family to call my own.
And it's all because you were there for me.
Thank you.
"Thank you," huh?
What did I do?
There, there! Hungry, are we?
There, there.
Right, I saved Hinazuki.
And then, we tried to make sure
Nakanishi Aya and Misato weren't alone.
Yashiro.
I've regained...
...my memories!
Kazu's a carpenter, huh?
Looks like both him and Osamu are working hard.
Yeah. By the way, Misato said
she'd come stop by here soon.
Really?
I thought she hated me.
Takes me back.
You had your ups and downs, huh?
Like that lunch money affair.
But, you know,
she was the one who suggested a fundraiser
to help with your hospital bills.
Really?
You were trying to save Misato that day.
You've remembered everything, haven't you?
Why didn't you tell us?
I didn't want to get you guys involved.
I mean, it's been fifteen years.
All the evidence is gone, and I doubt
anyone will believe anything I say.
Seeing you wake up after fifteen
years made me really happy.
I was simply overjoyed that you came back to us.
So I avoided asking you about the past.
You've fought enough already,
and I didn't want to disturb you while
your body and mind were still healing.
But if you're thinking about fighting
all by yourself again, don't.
Take us with you.
While Hiromi kept visiting you in the hospital,
he found his calling as a doctor.
I became a lawyer, and I'm still searching
for your attacker with Sawada-san.
You were our hero back then.
Our desire to catch up to you and fight
with you is what made us who we are today.
It was the same when we
helped Hinazuki, wasn't it?
You believed in me and gave
me your side of the story.
That's why I did my part and believed in you too.
It's for my own sake that I want to trust you.
Similar to someone wanting to be trusted,
but the other way around.
Airi...
That's right.
I have friends I can trust.
The killer is...
Yashiro.
I thought as much.
When I tapped my finger on
your wheelchair on the way here...
you stifled a reaction, didn't you?
Fifteen years ago...
you predicted my every move and foiled my plans.
That was far beyond...
...the level of a child.
It was as though you could see the future.
Yashiro!
I know what lies in your future!
Why?
How could you predict my thoughts?
What did you mean,
you knew what lies in my future?
Not like telling you would stop you from killing me.
I know what you're up to.
You have a cell phone in your pocket, right?
You're either recording this yourself,
or on the phone with someone who is.
I assume that someone is Kenya.
The statute of limitations has passed
on the case from fifteen years ago,
so you wanted to make me talk about cases
whose statute hadn't passed yet, right?
Unfortunately for you, they don't exist.
So you'll never be able to catch me, Satoru.
Look, you have a text from Kumi-chan.
Her IV drip starts at 4:30 p.m.
But today's bag is laced with muscle relaxants.
Of course, your fingerprints are on the bag, too.
You've granted a merciful death to a young
girl who was worried about her surgery.
And racked with guilt, I take my own
life by jumping off this rooftop.
Even if you told me how you
were able to predict my thoughts,
there's nothing you can do to save your own life.
But you can save Kumi-chan's life.
How do I know for sure that
you'll spare her life if I talk?
You don't, obviously.
But there is a possibility.
If you don't talk, you'll erase the possibility.
Too bad. We're out of time.
This was an all-or-nothing gamble for me as well.
But in the end, there was no particular
reason you foresaw my moves, huh?
It was all dumb luck.
What you said about knowing
what lies in my future was a bluff, too.
Rest assured.
I'll put all my heart into writing
your parting words to your mother.
Bye, Satoru. I've got a morning shift tomorrow,
so I'll see you in the afternoon.
Sleeping, huh?
Ma...
My memories have actually...
...returned, haven't they?
I know. It must've happened
when Kayo-chan visited.
She's a demon.
Hey, you didn't tell her to keep quiet, did you?
When Kenya-kun and Hiromi-kun left after their first visit,
I felt like I'd made a mistake.
'Cause you boys couldn't
speak from the heart that day.
When I saw Kayo-chan and her baby,
I couldn't bring myself to have her keep quiet.
I mean, she came to see you
after waiting fifteen long years.
Y'know, I looked at your face
and talked to you every single day.
But only when you started talking and
I noticed how much your voice had changed...
...did I realize that you'd grown up.
It made me so happy.
My baby boy is an adult now.
Mom...
I want to live life digging deep
and taking that extra step.
Bit late for that, don't you think?
That's how you lived your life even before the coma.
"Filling the holes in ourselves
is what life's all about."
That's part of the graduation day speech
I gave the sixth graders I was in charge of.
The day Hinazuki was placed
under protective custody,
I stood beside you and saw
your face in the falling snow.
That's the one look of yours
I remember most clearly.
My father left soon after I was born,
so I don't remember how he looked at all.
But back then, you took his place.
You were my father.
You filled the gaping hole in my heart.
I spent fifteen years waiting for you to wake up, too.
When I lost you, I also lost
the impulse that defined me.
I waited for so long.
But—
You're not alone anymore.
What decides this little game of ours?
The police catching you?
You killing me?
The game is already over.
And I'm pretty sure I won.
Hinazuki Kayo, Nakanishi Aya, Hiromi, and Yuuki-san...
I saved all of them.
Even Ma, whom you murdered in the future.
"Murdered in the future"?
What are you talking about?
You wanted to know how I could foil your plans?
It was because I know what lies in your future.
That's all there is to it.
That's why I could keep everyone safe.
That's why you couldn't kill
even one person connected to me.
Including myself.
I could've killed you anytime I pleased, Satoru.
I could kill you right now, too.
But for fifteen whole years, you didn't.
Because you needed me.
I was your purpose in life.
I was your hope.
I filled the gaping hole in your heart.
I beat you.
You're wrong!
Wrong, wrong!
This time's no different.
I'll win again!
You can't kill me.
Fifteen years is a long time.
I was asleep, so it went by in a flash for me,
but it must've felt like an eternity for you.
It's only because I'm around that you're alive.
That you feel alive.
I've repeated my life several times now.
You've killed several of my friends.
But I bear no hatred towards you anymore.
Because there's only one person in
this world who knows the real you.
Me.
You're right.
Satoru...
I can't...
...live without you anymore.
He was immediately arrested for attempted murder.
Is Kumi-chan all right?
Yeah, but we didn't tell her about Yashiro,
what with her surgery coming up and all.
Yeah.
"I believe" is such an odd turn of phrase, isn't it?
I mean, if you truly believed
from the bottom of your heart,
you wouldn't need to spell it out.
It's like saying, "I believe in air."
So people only say "they believe"
when they doubt something?
I'm not trying to say that "believing
in something" is a barefaced lie.
Just that they are words of hope
born from a desire to believe.
I lost my life between the ages of 11 to 25.
But the time I lost is my treasure.
In a town from which only I was erased,
my friends spent precious times
in their lives on my behalf.
You know heroes always arrive fashionably late.
Oh, there's Satoru.
You're late.
You're finally here.
Took you long enough!
As stupid as ever, I see.
A town from which only I was erased,
and a time from which only I was erased...
Those are my treasures.
This is great!
I love how you dig deep as you draw.
I'll keep going in that direction, then.
Sorry to have you come all the way here.
Are you leaving on a trip?
Yes.
I'm going back to Hokkaido to see some old friends.
Oh, really?
Well, have a great weekend.
I almost forgot.
Congratulations on the animated adaptation.
I make a living as a manga artist now.
I haven't experienced Revival since then.
Two weeks until the opening of
the 2010 Olympics in Vancouver...
I'm going for a walk.
See you later!
See you later.
Wait, they said we'd get even
more snowfall in the evening.
"My Hero," by Fujinuma Satoru.
I don't have the courage to
dig deep and take the first step.
That's why I don't have any allies.
I do have friends to have fun with,
but I think "friends" and "allies" are different.
Yesterday, I watched the final episode
of my favorite show, "Fight, Wonder Guy!"
At the start of the show, Wonder Guy fought alone.
He got knocked down again and again,
but he never gave up, and he mustered
up the courage to keep fighting.
"You can't carve open a path without
digging deep and taking the extra step,"
he said, and kept fighting.
And then, the people he moved with his
courage became his allies one by one.
That's why, even when it looked like he
was going to lose to the bad guy at the end,
he never stopped believing that
his allies would come to his aid.
But unlike Wonder Guy,
I don't have courage or allies.
So I felt extremely envious of him.
It made me want to grow up to have true allies
with whom I'd share a bond of trust.
It's really coming down, huh?
They said on TV it's the most snowfall
Kanto has had in a decade.
Mind if I take shelter from the snow with you?
I always believed.